

## Genn Osipenko

+1 (415) 570-8911 yo@genn.org http://genn.org/

Profile

15+ years of adapting information, information architecture, communication and user experience. Started as web designer/HTML coder and made up to creative director of the ad agency. Working all these years I found myself to be not a decorator, but a designer of information: my mission is to simplify perception and improve interaction. While creating several brands and conducting different campaigns for commercial brands and UNICEF I mastered my skill in communicating complicated things in simple ways. Understanding the way a product (mobile application, desktop application, web site, print ad etc.) is created I can design user interactions and create unique user experience at every stage of the product development. I examine digital behavior, analyze interests and needs to create products users love to use.

As an art and creative director I acquired the skill of leading design and creative team in the most productive way. I am very fond of sharing the experience, so I hold trainings and master classes.

Experience

UX Specialist, UI Designer, VideoGorillas; Kyiv, Ukraine/Los Angeles, USA – 2012–Present UXD cycle for web and iOS, iPad and mobile: analysis, strategy, design, wireframes, production (UXD support and control throughout the development, close collaboration with programmers). Created UI's and designing UX for web and mobile applications, related to video processing, live broadcasting and social communications. Hands-on responsive web design (prototyping and coding). In charge for all decisions about design, user experience and just good taste. Always eager and happy to help my colleagues, guide them through mystery of user oriented processes or just be ready with yet another mock up when it is needed.

National Consultant, UNICEF; Kyiv, Ukraine — 2010-Present

New Media, Branding and Communications consulting. Art director and designer collaboration. Consulting and audit on IT (backend and frontend) and UX/IA of the UNICEF's web and digital projects. Made several successful social ad campaigns with nationwide and international audience.

Art Director, 'Zerkalo Nedeli. Ukraina' Newspaper; Kyiv, Ukraine – 2011-2014

Art direction of the weekly newspaper. Created and composed infographics, designed the newspaper and special spreads. Designed and curated UX of daily news website.

Creative Director, 'Laboratory8' Creative Strategies Agency; Kyiv, Ukraine – 2005-2010 Started as designer and made the way up to art director, and then the head of creative department. I had creative team of 4 to 6 people. I created several successful brands, designed and curated design of several digital campaigns and websites, created identities for commercial clients and held meetings with clients.

Designer, 'Novy' TV Channel; Kyiv, Ukraine – 2004-2005

Designed and curated UX and UI of TV Channel website. Performed photo-editing for the daily news website, designed not website related things on demand.

Designer and Copywriter, 'ArtDept' Design Agency; Kyiv, Ukraine – 2005-2010 Designed websites, identities, wrote copy texts and described creative ideas. Also programmed for web using Flash and created print materials in InDesign.

UX and UI designer, Identity designer, Communications consultant, Print designer, Freelance Art Director, Various Clients as Freelancer; Kyiv, Ukraine – 1998-2012

Education

International Solomon University; Kyiv, Ukraine - Master of Computer Science, 2004

Skills

UX and UI design (site maps, process flows, wireframes, specifications etc.)
Brand and Identity creation
Creative and communicative strategies development
Adobe Creative Suite expert

Enough of working familiarity of HTML, CSS, Javascript, C, Xcode and other tools